GRADUATE CV EXAMPLE

BUSINESS ANALYST

Qualified Business Analyst with over 4 years of experience improving sales performance using business solution software and data analysis. Possess a B.A. in Business Administration. Seeking to utilise my strong prioritisation skills and analytical expertise to help contribute to the goals of your company.

KEY SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, Visio).
- Expert knowledge of SQL and relational database management systems.
- Skilled with Wrike and AtTask project management software.
- · Experienced with EDI standards and processing.
- Familiar with Agile software development methodology.

CONTACT



06923 612900



david.lorde@gmail.com



Ridgway St, Manchester, M40 7FY



linkedin.com/in/david.lorde

WORK EXPERIENCE

VALUENET, Reading, UK Business Analyst I January 2019 – Present

- Develop business architecture with consideration for scope, processes, alternatives, and risks.
- Analyse clients' business needs through document analysis, interviews, workshops, and workflow analysis.
- analysis.
 Conduct 5+ levels of testing to verify the client's needs are met, including functional, regression, user acceptance, integration and performance.
- Communicate client's business requirements by putting together easy-to-understand data and process models.

Whitley & Co., Reading, UK Business Analyst I May 2017 – December 2018

- Engage client to gather software requirements/business rules, and ensure alignment with development teams
- Translate stakeholder requirements into over 10 different tangible deliverables such as functional specifications, user cases, user stories, workflow/process diagrams, data flow/data model diagrams.
- Evaluate risks related to requirements implementation, testing processes, project communications, and training saving the company on average £3,000+ monthly.
- Identify and resolve errors in client data to ensure accurate business requirements.
- Draft and maintain business requirements and align them with technical requirements.
- Facilitate monthly meetings with clients to document requirements and explore potential solutions.

EDUCATION

The University of Manchester (2014-2017)

BS in Computer Science (First class honours)

Relevant Modules: Database Systems, Knowledge-based AI, System Architecture, Modelling Data on the

Web, Querying Data on the Web

Dissertation Topic: The Value of Data in Risk Management Assessment

King David High School, Manchester (2007-2014)

A-levels: Maths (A), Physics (A), Business Studies (A)

GCSEs: 10 A-C including Maths, Combined Science, and Design and Technology

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Amateur football player
- Spanish cooking
- Movie enthusiast